Thomas Barry

978-835-0951

thomasbarry594@gmail.com Personal Projects

SUMMARY:

Student at University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill with advanced background in Computer Science and Mathematics. I'm a hard-working and voracious learner. I love solving and finding optimal, efficient solutions to challenging coding problems. I have experience working on teams as well as building projects from scratch. My goal is to work with and learn from an experienced team of coders, and contribute to amazing projects.

EDUCATION:

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

(9/2019 - 12/2023)

• Carolina Scholarship/Dean's list/Honors College/Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

RELEVANT COURSE WORK:

- Analysis of Data Structures
- Software Engineering Laboratory
- Data Science in the Business World
- Computer Organization

- Modern Web Programming
- Analysis and Algorithms
- Discrete Structures
- Mathematical Analysis

MAJOR PROJECTS

- Personal finance project (in development)
 - o Thoroughly documented methods and tested code
 - o Added a GUI with menu for user to input information
 - o Designed program to scale, and saved to and read from files
- Personal finance project web (in development)
 - o Implemented web tool version using NodeJs that's hosted on a server
 - o Added navigation to multiple pages and second progress bar tool
- Custom responsive portfolio website hosted on GitHub (in development)
 - o Included CSS animations, multiple pages, and a downloadable pdf
- Java GUI application for TicTacToe, Connect4, and Othello games
 - o Implemented events and handlers and followed OOP best practices

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Wyzant

(10/2021 - Present)

- Created a private programming account on Wyzant
- Received an average of 5 stars out of 198 ratings
- Tutored students in Java programming, helping them complete assignments and better understand key concepts from recursion, to complex data structures, to JavaFX and Swing

PERSONAL PURSUITS:

Past Two Years

(05/2021 - Present)

- Taught myself HTML and CSS independently of my academic institution
- Competed in HackNC 2021 in a team of two and submitted a website hosting a Unity game
- Reached 6 kyu rank by completing coding challenges through the CodeWars website

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Coding Languages and Skills: Java, OOP, HTML, CSS, and NodeJs

Programming Tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ, Terminal, Visual Studio Code, and GitHub